A Guide to the Montgomery County [Virginia] Democratic Committee Records, 1961-1998
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Montgomery County [Virginia] Democratic Committee Records, 1961-1998
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Montgomery County Democratic Committee
Ms1989-061
10.3 Cubic Feet 8 boxes
This collection includes correspondence, newsclippings, meeting minutes, and rosters concerning the committee, local politics, and the congressional, senatorial, and presidential races of the 1970s, 1980s, and 1990s. Material date from 1961 through 1998.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The majority of the collection was donated to Special Collections in the late 1980s. Additional materials were received in several donations between 1992 and 1998.
Scope and Content
This collection includes correspondence, newsclippings, meeting minutes, and rosters concerning the committee, local politics, and the congressional, senatorial, and presidential races of the 1970s, 1980s, and 1990s. Material date from 1961 through 1998. The collection includes, but is not limited to, information about the specific campaigns and tenures of Rick Boucher (9th District Congressional Representative), L. Douglas Wilder (as Governor of Virginia, 1989-93), Al Gore and Bill Clinton (1992 Presidential campaign), Don Beyer (Lieutenant Governor campaign), Mary Sue Terry for Attorney General (1989) and Governor (1993), and Joan Munford and Jim Shuler for the 12th District Virginia House of Delegates.
Arrangement
This collection is largely in the original, chronological order in which it was received. Later accruals, donated in the 1990s, were organized by candidate and are in boxes 6-8 in chronological order.
Index Term
Subjects:
Montgomery County (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Women -- History
Contents List
- County Democratic Convention, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- State Board of Elections, 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Blank Stationery and Form Letters, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with State Electoral Board, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- State Democratic Office Holders, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Committee Meeting Minutes, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Montgomery County Democratic Committee, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- County Conventions and Mass Meetings, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sixth Legislature, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Officers of Election, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- State Central Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 37th Senatorial District, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fund Raising Dinners/Auctions, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Fund Raising Letter, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Contributions, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- District Meetings, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Misc. Forms, Correspondance, Lists, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Voter Lists, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence the State Headquarters Officials, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 9th District Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence from Mary Fessler, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 6th Legislative District Convention, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Newsclippings, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Polling, Registration, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Info RE Joseph T. Fitzpatrick, Chair of the State Central Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Clippings, Form Letters, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence to Sam Coleman, Chairman of the 9th District Congressional Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 9th Congressional District, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- 37th Senatorial District, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Radford Democratic Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Ways and Means Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Carroll County [VA] Democratic Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Floyd Democratic Party, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Misc. Correspondences, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence to Juanita Snipes, Chair of MCDP, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Delegates for the 6th Legislative Convention, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Party Dinner, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Virginia Election Laws, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Virginia Campaigns and Candidates, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- 6th Legislative Convention, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Virginia House of Delegates Nomination, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Newsclippings RE Local Political Issues, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Democratic Committee, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Democratic Committee, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 37th Senatorial District Convention, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mass Meeting, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Headquarter Sign-In Sheets, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Democratic Committee, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Democratic Committee, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Voter Registration, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Financial Records, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Financial Records, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Various Party Publications, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Ninth District Democratic Convention, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Democratic Committee Meetings and Bylaws, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mass Meeting, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- October 25 Governors Day Dinner, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- November 3, 1986 Montegomery Co. Democratic Committee Potluck Dinner, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Misc. Newspaper Clippings, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Mass Meetings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- November 3, 1987 - Election, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Spring 1987 - Nomination Meetings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Demo Memo Democratic Leader, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Committee Lists, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Registrar and Election Board, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "Demo Memo", 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Local Political Campaigns, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Voter Registration/Convention, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Al Gore (Presidential Candidate), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Election Date, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Ninth Congressional District, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Primary, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Calendar - Democratic Dates, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- January 23, 1988 MCDC Dinner, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- April 9, 1988 Democratic Caucus, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- June 3, 1988 VA. Beach State Convention, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- July 30, 1988 Democratic Picnic, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- September 7, Bentsen Rally, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- September - Headquarters, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- October 29, Governor's Day Reception and Dinner, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- October 29, Governor's Day Reception and Dinner, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Boucher Finance Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Assorted Democratic Literature, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Democratic Dates Calendar, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Doug Wilder, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Position Papers (Wilder, Beyer, Terry), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Don Beyer (Lt. Gov), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Richard L. Saslaw (Lt. Gov. Candidate), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Joan Munford and Charlie Johnson (House of Delegates), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Misc. Local Delegates, Board of Supervisors, Etc. Elections, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Election Publications, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- State Convention Material, June 9-10, 1989, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence to Gordon Bechanan RE 1989 Elections, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence to Gordon Bechanan/Inauguration, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Calendar 1990, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Democratic Leadership Council B Coalition for Democratic Values - Publications, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Publications, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Young Democrat State Convention, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Calendar, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Election Information - Misc., 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Republican Candidates Campaign Literature, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Local Independent Candidate Campaign Literature, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Local Democratic Candidate Campaign Literature, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- League of Women Voters, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Candidates, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Montgomery County Democratic Party/Committee, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Democratic Party of Virginia, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- National Democratic Party Literature, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Don Beyer 1993 Re-election for Lieutenant Governor, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Rick Bouchar General Literature, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Sylvia Cluto Campaign for Senator, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Bill Dolan Virginia Attorney General Election, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Howard Packett Campaign for House of Delegates, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Jim Shuler Election to House of Delegates, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Mary Sue Terry Election for Governor, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Bechanan, H. Gordon Personal Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 1993 Events, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 1993 - Dec. 11 Reorganization, 1993-12-11 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Election Day, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Headquarters, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- House and Supervisor Caucuses, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- State and Local Caucus, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- District C + D, 1993-06-05 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- 1992 Events, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- 9th District and State Convention, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Campaign and Election Day, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Headquarters, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Campaign and Election Day, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Dec. 7 Reorganization, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Petitions, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Delegate Caucus, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- 1991 Events, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Candidates, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Supervisors Cowst. Officers, 1991-08-24 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- 34th Senate Convention, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- 12 House Caucus, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Election Day, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- 1990 Events, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Implementing Agencies, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Mass Meeting, 1989-04-08 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- 9th District, 1989-05-06 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Mass Meeting, 1989-06-03 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- June 9-10 State Convention, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- 1989 Events, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- 1989 Recount, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- 1989 Headquarters, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- 1989 Coal Miners' Strike Information, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Mass Meeting, 1989-12-02 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- 1989 Presidential Primary, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- 1988 Presidential Candidates, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- 1988 Presidential Candidates - Al Gore, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- 1988 Presidential Candidates - Paul Simon, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Buttons and Advisements, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Minutes and Agendas, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
- Calendars, 1992-1995 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- 1988 Democratic National Convention Book, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Democratic National Convention, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Candidates, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Democratic Chair Handbook, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Candidates, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Candidates, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Officers of Election, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Candidates, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- 1994 Candidates - Chuck Robb, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Candidates, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10-13)
- Candidates - Rick Boucher, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Events, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Membership, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Candidates, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Events, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Campaign Materials - Beyer, Payne & Dolan, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Board of Supervisors, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Campaign Contributions, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Candidates, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Events, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Elections, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Recommendations, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Candidates - Rick Boucher, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)